VALIA LIU (CHENCHENG)

+1 (401)-263-1925 | cliu07@risd.edu valiaaa.github.io/cocoonstorage/

A Providence / Shanghai based graphic designer who does a variety of design works. I am keen to gain more professional experiences, especially within the field of publication and digital communication, and explore things that I am not yet familiar with. Beside my design work, I made a variety of handcraft pieces, like jewelry, sewing, knitting, and embroidery, which often become the inspirations of my design works.

SKILLS

- Layout / Typesetting
- · Visual Identity / Branding
- Visual Coding
- · Motion Graphic
- 3D Modeling
- Video Editing / Animation
- Printmaking

TOOLS

2D Design

- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- Indesign
- Lightroom
- Figma

3D Design

· Cinema 4D

Motion Design

- Premiere
- · Final Cut Pro
- · Basic After Effects

Others

- HTML / CSS
- · Microsoft Office
- Procreate

EDUCATION

Rhode Island School of Design | Sep 2019 – May 2023 | Providence, RI BFA Graphic Design

Honor Student for: Fall 2020, Spring 2021, Spring 2022

CREATIVE EXPERIENCES

Freelance | Sep 2016 - Current Graphic Designer / Artist

- Design yearbook cover for the class of 2019 of Shanghai Pinghe Bilingual School highschool department.
- Set visual system, poster series, and signature boards for multiple school activities like annual parties, halloween parties, and proms.
- Design recruitment posters for 6 student clubs.
- Design logo and a set of team-uniforms for the highschool frisbee team.
- Illustrate stop-motion opening and ending, banner, and avatar for a Youtube channel named "MicroNova".
- Customize illustration, pixel art, and handcrafts to around 130 customers.

Shanghai Symphony Orchestra | Jan 2019 – Feb 2019 | Shanghai, China Designer Assistant

- Research the references for exhibition arrangement and side-line products.
- Measure the scale of the exhibition space, and finish the first edition of the artwork arrangement.
- Design several visual possiblities for the side-line products, and finish four versions of design in two kinds of visual style.
- Modify posters of the upcoming orchestra performances.

Shiyuan Consulting Co.,Ltd | Apr 2019 – Jun 2019 | Shanghai, China Graphic Designer

- Design 5 posters for group activities of museum exhibitions.
- · Create visual layouts on social media.

OTHER EXPERIENCES

Rhode Island School of Design | Feb 2022 – May 2022, Sep 2022 – Dec 2022 RISO Printing Monitor | Providence, RI

- Communicate with students from a varied of majors, helping them to set the correct form of file for printing, and recommending the suitable printing options to their pieces.
- Set up every step for the printing manually, like change the ink chunk.

Rhode Island School of Design | Sep 2022 – Dec 2022 | Providence, RI Teaching Assistant for Design Studio 3

- Guide the junior graphic design majored students to build and refine their works conceptually and formly.
- Contribute on the structure of the class from a student's point of view during regular meeting with professors.

Rosso Fashion and Arts Education | Jul 2021 | Shanghai, China Teaching Assistant

- Document the key elements introduced in the courses and instructing student works.
- Record the performance and process of the students, and communicate with their guardians.